Welcome to this video. My name is Jonathan
Cassar and in this video I will be showing
how to use the application named Gamification
Research. The application is uploaded on the
Google Play store and a link can be found
in the description below.
Click the blue icon with the white star. The
main menu will appear. Here, the system shows
the total points, daily points and the days
elapsed. Underneath the buttons, the system
shows the level reached, badges earned and
the process achieved.
Before exploring further the application,
a number of parameters, must be inputted into
the system so that the application could function
appropriately. These parameters can be inputted
into the system through the settings screen
found in the top right corner.
Inside the setting screen, enter a user name
and an email address. Progress by enter the
dissertation length. In this case it is assumed
to be 15,000. Enter the introduction length
as a percentage of the total length e.g. 25%.
Do the same for the literature review (25%),
methodology (20%), results (25%) and finally
conclusion (15%). Progress by enter the number
of surveys to be conducted. In this case 200
surveys are to be conducted. Continue by enter
the starting date of the dissertation e.g.
1st September 2013.
The Notifications if ticked, will send notifications
every 6 hours starting at eight in the morning.
The Reset daily points if ticked, will reset
the daily points. The Reset if ticked, will
reset all data stored in the application.
Back to the main menu, the system will now
reflect the inputted data. Now that the system
is set up, actions can be conducted to earn
points, level-up and earn badges. Actions
consist of reading papers, writing chapters
and conducting surveys.
Let's start by exploring the paper's section.
Click the paper's button to enter the paper's
section. Here, 15 points can be earned with
every read performed. Click on the orange
buttons, e.g. paper 1 to display the paper's
abstract. Read through the physical paper
and once ready hit the Read button to earn
15 points. Note how the button changed from
orange to green to mark a state of completion.
Navigating back to the main menu, it can be
seen how the total and daily points increased
to reflect the points earned. Back to the
Papers Progress Screen, if the wrong button
has been clicked by mistake, the action can
be reverted. Say paper 3 was wrongly clicked,
click the green icon again and the original
sate of the button will be restored.
Click the blue icon with the question mark
symbol found in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen. The popup window provides hints
and actions that can be performed.
Now Let's explore the points earn from writing.
From the main menu, click the Progress button.
The Introduction, Literature Review, Methodology,
Results and Conclusion are displayed. The
numbers in brackets show the amount of words
to be written for each chapter to be considered
as completed. To the left of the progress
bar, buttons in red colour are displayed.
These buttons, change colour according to
the level of completeness. Red indicates a
low level of completeness. Yellow indicates
half way through. Green indicates almost completeness.
Click the blue icon with the question mark
symbol found in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen. The popup window provides hints
and actions that can be performed.
Points are earned by writing the dissertation
report. The more written text, the higher
the points earned. If for example 1000 words
from the Introduction chapter are written,
points can be earned by sliding the slider
to the left. This increases the word count
found beneath the slider and changes the colour
of the buttons. Navigating back to the main
menu, it can be seen how the total and daily
points increased to reflect the points earned.
Now Let's explore the Evaluation.
Click the Evaluation screen to display the
Evaluation Progress. Here, points are earned
by completing surveys. With each survey completed,
2 points will be earned. The total number
of surveys which needs to be completed are
displayed at the bottom of the screen. Beneath,
are the daily points earned from surveys along
with some hints. Hints change according to
the number of surveys completed and provide
guidelines on how the response can be further
increased.
If for example 20 surveys have been conducted,
rotating the wheel in a clockwise fashion
will change the progress bar colour from dark
red to light green. The number of completed
survey at the centre of the wheel increases
to mark the progress.
Click the blue icon with the question mark
symbol found on the bottom right hand corner
of the screen. The popup window provides hints
and actions that can be performed.
Finally let's explore the Calendar
No points can be earned here. The purpose
of this section is to display the daily events
entered through the gmail calendar. Given
the daily commitments and 8 hours of sleep,
the application suggests the time available
to work on the dissertation. No excused to
procrastinate.
To Recap
The purpose of the application is to gamify
the dissertation writing process. Points,
badges and levelling up can be earned by reading
papers, writing text and conduct surveys.
I hope this was informative for you, and I
would like to thank you for viewing.